

ABOUT ME

Democracy Entrepreneur | Election Administration Expert & Innovator Author | Speaker | Civic Engagement Enthusiast

I believe in designing voter-centric processes that put the voter first. As an experienced election official and former Director of Elections for the City and County of Denver, I know how to improve systems to make them more responsive and effective for voters and customers. Under my leadership, Denver Elections was transformed to become one of the top election offices in the country, earning international and national recognition for various technical innovations. We created systems to better serve voters such as Ballot TRACE and eSign and increased transparency and accountability in the process. I also played an integral role in the 2013 Election Modernization Reforms that have made Colorado one of the top states for security, voter registration, and voter engagement.

Elections are about people and process. I believe we must continually improve the entire election system which will lead to higher engagement, increased public confidence in elections and in government, and more effective service for the public.

Amber McReynolds

Denver, Colorado, USA amber@voteathome.org

@AmberMcReynolds

M medium.com/@ambermcreynolds

in linkedin.com/in/ambermcreynolds

Co-Author When Women Vote, Release: November 2019

Experience

Executive Director | Vote at Home Institute VoteAtHome.org | @VoteAtHome

The Vote at Home Institute is a non-profit non-partisan 501(c)(3), created to increase voter engagement by supporting and encouraging the effective implementation of Vote at Home systems, policies, and laws across the United States. Vote at Home systems provide for convenient, secure, and accessible voting processes.

Election Official | Director of Elections City and County of Denver, CO (2005-2018) DenverVotes.org | @ DenverElections

As the Director of Elections with the City and County of Denver, CO I oversaw pivotal elections and developed innovative techniques in election administration which earned the office numerous awards.

Regional Project Manager, New Voters Project, Iowa (2004-2005)

Program Director, 14th Judicial Circuit, State of Illinois, (2002-2004)

Parliamentary Research Associate, United Kingdom Parliament - UK Solicitor General, Rt. Hon. Harriet Harman, QC MP, London, England (2000-2002)

Education

Masters of Science | Comparative Politics | London School of Economics & Political Science | 2002

Bachelor of Arts | Political Science and Speech Communications | University of Illinois | 2001

Skills

Leadership

Executive Experience

Public Speaking

Election Official

Innovator

Strategy

Data Analytics

Policy Innovation

Project Management

Strategic Communication

Boards

MIT Election Data Science Lab **Advisory Board**

Election Validation Project Advisor

City Year Denver Board of Directors

LIFT Colorado Board of Directors

Empowerment Council, Women's Foundation of Colorado

Colorado Women's Chamber of Commerce Public Policy Committee

Awards

2018 Public Official of the Year -**Governing Magazine**

ICPS – International Center for Parliamentary Studies - 2017

ICPS – International Center for Parliamentary Studies - 2015

EAC Clearie Award - 2017

Election Center Eagle's Award for Technology – 2017

Election Center Democracy Award for Innovation – 2015, 2013

NACO Achievement Award - 2013

Michelle Burton Excellence in Election Service Award - 2015

Publications/Speeches

Voter-Centered Approach to Election Administration

Medium.com | June 2018

Opinion: Amendments Y and Z let us do what's right instead of fighting about who's right

Colorado Sun | October 2018

Trump's Voter Commission is Frightening Away Denver Voters

Denver Post | July 2017

<u>View It from a Different Angle – How to Improve Efficiency While</u> **Serving Voters Better**

U.S. Elections Assistance Commission | December 2015

Innovating the Voter Experience

RepresentUS | March 2018

Governing by the Numbers – Pew and Route Fifty

Pew/Route Fifty Event | October 2016

Denver – New Voting System Video

Denver Elections Video | May 2015

News

Revolutionizing the Voting Process

Comcast NBC Newsmakers | January 2019

How Treating Voting Like a Business Could Actually Improve It

Colorado Biz Magazine | September 2019

Model City: Denver Cleaned Up Its Voter Rolls & Boosted Turnout, Too

NBC News | August 2017

Denver Wins Another International Election Administration Award

City and County of Denver | January 2017

Denver County Elections Division Honored With a "Clearie" Award For **Election Innovation**

U.S. Election Assistance Commission | November 2017

Illinois Elections Officials Explore Vote by Mail Programs

Block Club Chicago | October 2018

Denver Elections Director & CIO Share Advice to Secure Elections

Efficient Gov | October 2018

Cybersecurity and Elections

NPR | February 2018

Increasing Voter Turnout for 2018 and Beyond

New York Times | June 2017

Mail Ballot Election Returns

Chicago Tribune | October 2018

How other states have modernized elections offers lessons for Florida

Miami Herald | January 2016

Amber to Leave Denver Elections

Colorado Politics | August 2018